Inventory of the Chen Lifu typescript: The storm clouds clear over China: the memoir of Chen Li-fu
Hoover Institution Archives
Chen Lifu typescript: The storm clouds clear over China: the memoir of Chen Li-fu, 1900-1993
1911-2004
2006C58
Hoover Institution Archives
8 manuscript boxes (3.2 linear feet)
The collection includes drafts, working materials, and correspondence associated with the translation, editing, and publication of Lifu's memoir. Edited and compiled by Sidney H. Chang and Ramon H. Myers and published by the Hoover Institution Press, the memoir and collection materials relate to political conditions in China and Taiwan. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Chen, Lifu.
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Chinese politician; secretary to Chiang Kai-shek, 1926 to 1949.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is composed of documents relating to political conditions in China and Taiwan. Additionally, it includes drafts, working papers, and correspondence associated with the translation, editing, and publication of Chen Lifu's memoir. The memoir was edited and compiled with an introduction and notes by Sidney H. Chang and Ramon H. Myers and published by the Hoover Institution Press.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Chang, Hsu-hsin.; Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; Myers, Ramon Hawley, 1929-; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Taiwan--Politics and government.
- Correspondence File, 1950-2004
  - Acceptance of memoir for publication by the Hoover Institution, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Chiang Kai-Chek and Chen Lifu on Communism, 1950 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Chen Lifu and Sidney Chang on promoting Confucianism in Russia, 1997 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Chen Lifu and Sidney Chang on stipends for Chang's research work, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Chen Lifu and W. W. Rostow, 1964 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Chen Lifu's agreement with Sidney Chang and the Hoover Institution, 1991 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Regarding the publication of Chen Lifu's memoir.
  - Chen Lifu's letters to Sidney Chang, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Regarding application for a grant from Chiang Ching-kuo Foundation.
  - Chen Lifu's letters to Sidney Chang, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    Regarding instructions on contract with Hoover Institution.
  - Invitations, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Chen, Chang, and Myers on researching and writing of the memoir, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Sidney Chang on international conference on Chen Lifu's memoir in Hong Kong, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Problems with publicity, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Sidney Chang's grant application: Chiang Ching-kuo Foundation for International Scholarly Exchange, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Sidney Chang's application: Pacific Cultural Foundation, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Translations and publication, 1992-2004 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Reports File, 1946-1976
  - CIA Research Reports on China, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - CIA records, "Shanghai Municipal Police Investigation Files, 1894-1944," in UC Southern Regional Library Facility Microfilm, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - U.S. State Department, Central Files, China Internal Affairs, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - External Affairs Monthly Bulletin of the Department of External Affairs, Ottawa, Canada, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Reports from U.S. Embassy in China to the State Department, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - U.S. Military Intelligence Reports: China (Part I and II), 1911-1941 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
- Subject File, 1932-1993
  - First ceremony of the Lifu Academic Award for Chinese Medicine, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Commission of Inquiring on the League of Nations, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Apparatus of the Kuomingtang and the Nationalist government, 1933-1949 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Notes on Chen Lifu's memoir, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - The unification of China after World War II, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Speeches and Writings File, 1966-1994
  - "A Study of Chinese Characters," Chen Lifu, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "On Nation-Building through Education," Chen Lifu, undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Charles Kitt's PhD dissertation chapters, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Chen Lifu's editing notes on the memoir, undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - "Confucianism, Education and Economic Development in Taiwan," Chen Lifu and Hou Ching-ming, 1989 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Draft notes and addenda to publication, circa 1993 (Reading room workstation)
  - Drafts of Chen Lifu's speeches in U.S., 1991 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - "Four Years of Chinese Education (1937-1941)," Chen Lifu (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Interview: Chen Lifu and Sidney Chang, 1991 August-December (Box-folder 4: 9-10)
  - Chen Lifu's memoir, chapter one, undated (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Preface and table of contents, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Chen Lifu's memoir, chapters 1-6, undated (Box-folder 5: 2-7)
  - "Interview with Professor Te-kong Tong on Chen Lifu's memoir," Sidney Chang, 1994 December (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Lifu's memoir, preliminary draft, chapters 1-2, undated (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
  - Lifu's memoir (5th draft), 1993 February (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Lifu's memoir (7th draft), chapters 1-2, 1993 April (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Lifu's memoir, chapters 1-2, undated (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
  - "Philosophy of Modernization," Chen Lifu, 1966 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "Chinese Philosophy and Russian Political Culture -- From Legalism to Confucianism,", 1999 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - "The Golden Mean and Chinese Culture," Chen Lifu, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - "The Future of the Commission on Land Research and Planning," Chen Lifu, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - "Why Confucius Has Been Reverenced as the Model Teacher of All Ages," Chen Lifu, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 5)
- Printed Matter, 1925-1985
  - Bibliography of published works on modern Chinese history, undated (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Chinese National Party Monthly Journal, 1925 January (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Excerpt from Historical Dictionary of Modern China, 1985 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Foreign Relations, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - John K. Fairbank obituary, 1991 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - News clippings, 1932-1998 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Excerpts: History of Republican China, 1968-1987 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Time Magazine and New World News with Chen Lifu on cover, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 8: 13)